Toby Glover

540.817.1915 | William.Glover@Tufts.edu | GitHub: wtglover

OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

As a Tufts University undergrad, I intend to leverage my education and full time work experience to find a quality summer internship focusing on the web stack and continue to develop my skills in backend programming and API development.

EDUCATION

Tufts University School of Engineering, Boston

Expected May 2019

B.S. in Computer Science

GPA: 3.50 / 4.00, Dean's List (Fall 2015 - Present)

Relevant course work: Data Structures, Algorithms, Web Programming, Machine Structures and Assembly Language Programming, Android Mobile Development, Calculus

Rockbridge County High School, Lexington, VA

August 2010 - June 2014

Advanced Studies Diploma, GPA: 3.95 / 4.00

Summer coursework:

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Summer 2013

Courses in Electrical and Computer Engineering and Sound Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Switch Media

Australia's industry leader in storing, encoding, and distributing live and on-demand video content via its SaaS platform.

Application Architect and Developer

October 2015 - May 2016

September 2014 - May 2016

Medford, MA

- · Designed and built Presto, an Australian video on demand service similar to Hulu, for the Roku streaming platform on contract basis
- · Performed code reviews on the two other members of development team

Support Engineer and Back-End Programmer

September 2014 - May 2015

Sydney, Australia

- · First point of contact for clients including Foxtel, the largest cable company in Australia
- · Sole on-site representative of Switch Media to provide support to Yahoo! 7 at the Australian Open Tennis Tournament in Melbourne, where Switch provided live streams for all 14 courts
- · Built custom internal and client-facing web tools using PHP, HTML, JavaScript
- · Wrote server-side scripts to analyze internal workflow data and determine bottlenecks

Camp Foley

June - August 2016 (9 weeks)

Camp Counselor and Trip Leader

Pine River, MN

- · Planned and executed events for approximately 160 people
- · Taught high-intensity activities including archery and rock climbing

Washington & Lee University

September 2013 - March 2014

Lexington, VA

Intern in Sound Engineering Studio

· Built amplifiers and other recording equipment

· Sole engineer on various recording sessions, both in the studio and live

SKILLS

Languages BrightScript (Roku proprietary language), C/C++, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,

Python, Java, LaTex

Frameworks Django, Node, MySQL, MongoDb

Tools Unix, Apache, Git & Github, SVN, Android Studio

ATHLETIC AND EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Tufts Marathon TeamSeptember 2016 - PresentTufts Computer Science ExchangeSeptember 2015 - PresentTufts Democrats ClubSeptember 2015 - Present